[Music]
hi everybody welcome back to the channel
as you can see
we're going a bit
beardy
christmas is coming just saying
anyway this week we're gonna do a vegan
pistachio ice cream we're gonna use elm
lee's plant-based double cream
substitute and some oat cream as well
really good combo so stick around we'll
show you how to make it
[Music]
first thing we're going to do is toast
our pistachios in the oven at 150 c
for six to eight minutes make sure they
don't burn at this stage though
once they're ready take them out the
oven and let them cool down slightly for
five to ten minutes so to your blender
add 80 grams of those toasted pistachios
and pulse them to start with and then
blend them on high into a super smooth
paste now this might take a while and
they also might not blend particularly
well if they don't then add some simple
syrup just a small amount at a time and
keep going i mean some places on the
internet tell you not to add liquid to
this ignore that you can add liquid you
just need to keep going until it comes
together that for my case that took
nearly 15 minutes but what was left was
a really super smooth pistachio paste
[Music]
put your pistachio paste aside and now
we're going to start working on the rest
of the base
so add 200 milliliters of water 180
grams of sugar and 5 grams of corn syrup
to a pan and heat gently just to
dissolve the sugars
then add 250 milliliters of the oat
cream i'll put a link down below for
this
and 80 grams of your pistachio paste
just gently warm this through but note
the mix will not be smooth at this stage
remove it from the heat and get an
immersion blender out or go to town with
a balloon whisk like i've done
once it's properly emulsified add the
250 milliliters of elm lee vegan cream
two milliliters of almond extract
and stir it all together really well
before putting it in the fridge for a
few hours
[Music]
once the base is chilled churn it in
your machine and add the chopped
pistachios right at the end of the churn
loading the tub up when it's soft serve
stage
[Music]
for those that are quick with the eye
you'll notice i'm wearing my cookie
monster lounge pants
sunday morning as always
here we are straight out of the freezer
we're gonna get some scooped up and see
what this has turned out like
[Music]
i thought we'd try a new shot with a
scooping procedure so let us know what
you think
now
this is not the first recipe i've made
with the elmly
vegan or plant-based double cream i know
it's really really good stuff and when
you compare it to what's available in
the us which i think is a silk brand
which isn't quite as good as this i've
never tried it
i don't know how you compare the two
because they're they're not available in
the same places but
somehow i'll figure it out we're going
to canada next year so i might even you
know try and wang all my way into
someone's ice cream machine and make
some over there who knows let's just try
this and see what it's like
[Music]
that is bloody good
one thing to know about this one
we've not gone too mad with the
almond extract some vegan ice cream they
load it with almond extract and that's
what you taste rather than pistachios
but this
just a very slight gentle roasting of
those pistachios really brings that
flavor out so it actually overpowers the
almond extract really well you taste
pistachio
you taste a little bit of the almond
extract but it's just enough to bring
the flavour forward a little bit more
it's really creamy
the lovely little bite of those
pistachio nuts in there if you don't
roast the pistachios and you mix them in
they go really soggy so just roast them
that little bit and they'll stay nice
and crunchy
i mean this is really good i mean this
is this is very very
good ice cream regardless of whether
it's vegan or not
you could put this in front of anyone
and they'd never tell that it's not
dairy ice cream
super creamy super creamy
so
if you're into vegan ice cream or if you
just want to try this one
this is a really good recipe so i hope
you do try it let us know what you think
don't forget to like and subscribe and
we'll see you next week